ALEX:
There was me.
That is, Alex,
and my three droogs.
That is, Pete, Georgie and Dim.
And we sat in the
Korova Milk Bar...
...trying to make up
our rassoodocks...
...what to do with the evening.
The Korova Milk Bar sold milk plus.
Milk plus vellocet or
synthemesc or drencrom...
...which is what we were drinking.
This would sharpen you up...
...and make you ready for a bit
of the old ultra-violence.
[MAN SINGING DRUNKENLY]
ALEX:
One thing I could never stand...
...was to see a filthy,
dirty old drunkie...
...howling away at the
filthy songs of his fathers...
...and going "blerp blerp"
in between...
...as it might be a filthy old
orchestra in his stinking guts.
I could never stand to see anyone
like that, whatever his age.
But more especially when he
was real old, like this one was.
[GUYS CHEERING]
MAN: Can you spare some cutter,
me brothers?
[GUYS LAUGH]
Go on! Do me in,
you bastard cowards!
I don't want to live anyway.
Not in a stinking world
like this.
Oh?
And what's so stinking about it?
It's a stinking world because
there's no law and order anymore!
It stinks because it lets
the young get onto the old...
...like you done!
It's no world
for an old man any longer.
What kind of a world is it
at all?
Men on the moon.
Men spinning around the earth.
And there's not no
attention paid...
...to earthly
law and order no more.
[SINGING DRUNKENLY]
[ALL SHOUTING]
[WOMAN SCREAMING]
MAN: Right. Get her clothes.
WOMAN: No!
ALEX: lt was at the derelict casino
that we came across Billy-boy...
...and his four droogs.
They were about to perform
a little of the old...
...in-out, in-out on a weepy
young devotchka they had there.
No!
[BOTTLE CLATTERING]
ALEX:
Ho, ho, ho!
Well, if it isn't...
...fat, stinking...
...billy goat
Billy-boy in poison.
How are thou...
...thou globby bottle of cheap,
stinking chip-oil?
Come and get one in the yarbles...
...if you have any yarbles...
...you eunuch jelly, thou.
Let's get them, boys!
MAN:
Yahoo!
Subtitle | www.movieddl.me
[SIRENS WAILING]
[ALEX WHISTLES]
ALEX:
The police!
Come on. Let's go!
ALL:
Yahoo!
ALEX: The Durango 95 purred away
real horror show.
A nice, warm vibratey feeling
all through your guttiwuts.
Soon it was trees and dark,
my brothers...
...with real country dark.
Whoo-hoo!
[TIRES SCREECHING & HORN HONKING]
Yahoo!
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
[TIRES SCREECHING & HORN HONKING]
ALEX: We fillied around with other
travelers of the night...
...playing Hogs of the Road.
Then we headed west.
What we were after now
was the old surprise visit.
That was a real kick...
...and good for laughs and
lashing of the old ultra-violent.
[GUYS CHEERING & SHOUTING]
[DOORBELL RINGS]
Who on earth could that be?
I'll go and see.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
Yes, who is it?
ALEX: Excuse me, can you please help?
There's been a terrible accident!
My friend's bleeding to death!
Can I please use your telephone?
We don't have a telephone.
You'll have to go somewhere else.
ALEX: But, missus, it's a matter
of life and death!
Who is it, dear?
WOMAN: A young man.
He says there's been an accident.
He wants to use the telephone.
I suppose you better let him in.
WOMAN:
Wait a minute, will you?
I'm sorry, but we don't usually
let strangers in--
[GUYS LAUGHING]
[GUYS CHEERING & SHOUTING]
What do you want from me?
[ALEX WHISTLES]
ALEX: Pete, check the rest
of the house. Dim...
[ALEX SINGING GENE KELLY'S
"SINGIN' IN THE RAIN"]
WOMAN:
Ah!
[ALEX HUMMING]
[ALEX RESUMES SINGING
GENE KELLY'S "SINGIN' IN THE RAIN"]
DIM:
Ready for love.
Viddy well, little brother.
Viddy well.
[MAN GRUNTING]
ALEX: We were all feeling a bit
shagged and fagged and fashed...
...it having been an evening
of some small energy expenditure.
So we got rid of the auto...
...and stopped at the Korova
for a nightcap.
Hello, Lucy.
Had a busy night?
We've been working hard too.
Pardon me, Luce.
[FLUID TRICKLING]
ALEX: There was some sophistos from
the TV studios around the corner...
...laughing and govoreeting.
The devotchka smeched away...
...not caring about
the wicked world one bit.
Then the disk on the stereo
twanged off and out.
And in the short silence
before the next one came on...
...she suddenly came
with a burst of singing.
[SINGING FROM BEETHOVEN'S
"9TH SYMPHONY"]
ALEX: And it was, like,
for a moment, my brothers...
...some great bird
had flown into the milk bar.
And I felt all the malenky
little hairs on my plott...
...standing endwise.
And the shivers crawling up
like slow, malenky lizards...
...and then down again.
Because I knew what she sang.
It was a bit from
the glorious "9th" by Ludwig van.
[MAKES FARTING NOISE]
[GRUNTING & GROANING]
What did you do that for?
For being a bastard
with no manners.
Without a dook of an idea about how
to comport yourself public-wise.
I don't like you should
do what you done.
And I'm not your brother no more
and wouldn't want to be.
Watch that.
Do watch that...
...if to continue to be on live
thou dost wish.
Yarbles!
Great, bouncy yarblockos to you!
I'll meet you with chain
or nozh or britva anytime.
I'm not having you aiming
tolchocks at me reasonless.
It stands to reason,
I won't have it.
A nozh scrap anytime you say.
Doobidoob.
A bit tired maybe.
Best not to say more.
Bedways is right ways now.
So best we go home ways
and get a bit of spatchka.
Right, right?
PETE & GEORGIE:
Right, right.
ALEX:
ALEX: Where I lived was with
my dada and mum...
...in municipal flat block
18-A, Linear North.
ALEX:
It had been a wonderful evening.
And what I needed now
to give it the perfect ending...
...was a bit
of the old Ludwig van.
[CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING ON STEREO]
ALEX:
Oh, bliss!
Bliss and heaven!
It was gorgeousness and
gorgeosity made flesh.
It was like a bird
of rarest spun heaven metal.
Or like silvery wine
flowing in a spaceship...
...gravity all nonsense now.
As I slooshied...
...I knew such lovely pictures.
Alex. Alex!
Alex?
What do you want?
MOTHER:
It's past 8, Alex.
You don't want to be
late for school, son.
Bit of a pain in the gulliver, Mum.
Leave us be,
and I'll try and sleep it off.
And then I'll be as right
as dodgers for this after.
But you've not been
to school all week, son.
ALEX:
Got to rest, Mum.
Got to get fit.
Otherwise, I'm liable
to miss a lot more school.
MOTHER: I'll put your
breakfast in the oven.
I've got to be off meself now.
All right, Mum.
Have a nice day at the factory.
He's not feeling too good
again this morning, Dad.
Yes. Yes, I heard.
You know what time he got in?
No, I don't.
I'd taken me sleepers.
I wonder...
...where exactly is it
he goes to work of evenings.
Well, like he says...
...it's mostly odd things he does.
Helping-like...
...here and there, as it might be.
Hi, hi, hi, Mr. Deltoid.
Funny surprise, seeing you here.
Alex-boy.
Awake at last, yes?
I met your mother
on the way to work, yes?
She gave me the key.
She said something about
a pain somewhere.
Hence, not at school, yes?
A rather intolerable pain
in the head, brother sir.
It should be clear
by this after lunch.
Or certainly by this evening, yes.
The evening's the great time,
isn't it, Alex-boy?
- Cup of the old chai, sir?
- No time, yes.
Sit, sit, sit!
To what do I owe
this extreme pleasure, sir?
Anything wrong, sir?
Wrong? Why should you
think of anything being wrong?
Have you been doing
something you shouldn't?
Just a manner of speech.
Yes, well, it's just a manner
of speech from your...
...post-corrective advisor to you
that you watch out, little Alex.
Because next time it's not
going to be the corrective school.
Next time it'll be the Barley place,
and all my work ruined.
If you've no respect
for yourself...
...you at least might have some
for me, who sweated over you.
A big, black mark, I tell you,
for every one we don't reclaim.
A confession of failure
for every one of you...
...who ends up in the stripy hole.
I've been doing nothing I shouldn't.
The millicents have nothing
on me, brother.
Sir, I mean.
DELTOID: Cut out this clever
talk about millicents.
Just because the police
haven't picked you up...
...doesn't mean that you've not
been up to some nastiness.
There was a bit
of nastiness last night.
Some very extreme nastiness, yes?
A few of a certain Billy-boy's
friends were ambulanced off late.
Your name was mentioned.
The words got to me
by the usual channels.
Certain friends of yours
were named also.
Nobody can prove anything
about anybody, as usual.
I'm warning you, little Alex...
...being a good friend
to you as always...
...the one man in this
sore and sick community...
...who wants to save you
from yourself!
[ALEX GROANING]
What gets into you all?
We've been studying the problem
for damn well near a century.
But we get no farther
with our studies.
You got a good home here.
Good, loving parents.
You've got not too bad of a brain.
Is it some devil
that crawls inside of you?
ALEX:
Nobody's got anything on me.
I been out of the millicents'
rookers for a long time.
That's just what worries me.
A bit too long to be safe.
You're about due, by my reckoning.
That's why I'm warning you...
...to keep your handsome
young proboscis out of the dirt.
Do I make myself clear?
ALEX:
As an unmuddied lake, sir.
As clear as an azure sky
of deepest summer.
You can rely on me, sir.
Ugh.
[GROANS]
[TAPPING CANE]
ALEX:
Excuse me, brother.
I ordered this two weeks ago.
Can you see if it's arrived?
Just a minute.
Pardon me, ladies.
Enjoying that, are you, my darling?
A bit cold and pointless,
isn't it, my lovely?
What's happened to yours,
my little sister?
[GIRL LAUGHS]
Who you getting, bratty?
Goggly Gogol? Johnny Zhivago?
The Heaven 17?
What you got back home
to play your fuzzy warbles on?
I bet you've got little
pitiful, portable picnic players.
Come with Uncle
and hear all proper.
Hear angel trumpets
and devil trombones.
You are invited.
- Hi, hi, hi, there.
- Well, hello.
He are here!
He have arrived!
Hooray!
Welly, welly, welly,
welly, welly, welly, well!
To what do I owe
the extreme pleasure...
...of this surprising visit?
We got worried.
[DIM LAUGHING]
GEORGIE:There we were, waiting and
drinking at the old knifey moloko...
...and you had not turned up.
And we thought
you might have been, like...
...offended by something
or other.
So around we come to your abode.
Appy Polly loggies.
I had something of a pain
in the gulliver, so I had to sleep.
I was not awakened
when I gave orders for wakening.
DIM:
Sorry about the pain.
Using the gulliver
too much-like, maybe.
[DIM CHUCKLES]
Giving orders and
discipline and such, perhaps.
You sure the pain is gone?
You sure you'd not
be happier back in bed?
[DIM CHUCKLES]
Let's get things nice
and sparkling clear.
This sarcasm,
if I may call it such...
...does not become you,
my little brothers.
As I am your droog and leader...
...I'm entitled to know
what goes on.
Yeah.
Now then, Dim.
What does that great big
horsey gape of a grin portend?
All right, no more
picking on Dim, brother.
That's part of the new way.
New way?
What's this about a new way?
There's been some very large talk
behind my sleeping back, and no error.
If you must have it,
have it, then.
We go around shop crasting
and the like...
...coming out with a pitiful
rookerfull of money each.
And Will the English
in the coffee mesto...
...saying he can fence anything
any malchick tries to crast.
The shiny stuff. The Ice!
The big, big money's available,
is what Will the English says.
Big, big money.
And what will you do
with the big, big, big money?
Have you not everything you need?
If you need a motorcar,
you pluck it from the trees.
If you need pretty Polly,
you take it.
Brother, you think and talk
sometimes like a little child.
Little child, yeah.
Tonight we pull a man-size crast.
Tonight's a man-size crast!
ALEX:
Good! Real horror show!
Initiative comes
to thems that wait.
I've taught you much,
my little droogies.
Now tell me what you had in mind,
Georgie-boy.
The old moloko plus first.
Would you not say?
- Something to sharpen us up.
- Some of them moloko plus.
GEORGIE: You especially.
We have the start.
Yeah, we got a start on you!
Yeah, moloko plus, eh?
[LAUGHING]
ALEX: As we walked along
the flat block marina...
...I was calm on the outside,
but thinking all the time.
So now it was to be
Georgie the General...
...saying what we should do
and what not to do.
And Dim as his mindless,
grinning bulldog.
But suddenly I viddied that
thinking was for the gloopy ones...
...and that the oomny ones
used, like...
...inspiration and what Bog sends.
For now it was lovely music
that came to my aid.
There was a window open
with a stereo on...
...and I viddied right at once
what to do.
I had not cut into any
of Dim's main cables.
And so with the help
of a clean tashtook...
...the red, red kroovy
soon stopped.
And it did not take long to
quieten the two wounded soldiers...
...down in the snug
of the Duke of New York.
Now they knew who was
master and leader.
Sheep, thought I.
But a real leader knows
always when, like...
...to give and show generous
to his unders.
Well...
Now we're back to where we were.
Yes?
Just like before,
and all forgotten?
Right, right, right?
Right.
Well, Georgie-boy...
...this idea of yours for tonight.
Tell us all about it, then.
GEORGIE:
Not tonight.
Not this nochy.
Come, come, come, Georgie-boy.
You're a big, strong chelloveck,
like us all.
We're not little children,
are we, Georgie-boy?
What, then, didst thou
in thy mind have?
GEORGIE:
It's this health farm.
A bit out of the town.
Isolated.
It's owned by this rich ptitsa...
...who lives there with her cats.
The place is shut down
for a week...
...and she's completely on her own.
It's full up with, like,
gold and silver...
...and, like, jewels.
ALEX:
Tell me more, Georgie-boy.
Tell me more.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
WEATHERS:
Oh, shit!
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
WEATHERS:
Who's there?
ALEX:
Excuse me, can you please help?
There's been a terrible accident!
Can I please use your telephone
for an ambulance?
I'm frightfully sorry.
There's a telephone in the
public house a mile down the road.
I suggest you use that.
ALEX:
But missus, this is an emergency!
It's a matter of life and death!
Me friend's lying in the middle
of the road, bleeding to death!
I'm very sorry...
...but I never open the door
to strangers after dark.
ALEX:
Very well, madam.
You can't be blamed
for being suspicious...
...with so many scoundrels
and rogues of the night about.
I'll try and get help
at the pub, then.
I'm sorry if I disturbed you.
Thank you very much.
Good night.
ALEX:
Dim, bend down.
I'll get in that window
and open the front door.
[DIALING PHONE]
Hello. Radlett Police Station?
Good evening. It's Miss Weathers
at Woodmere Health Farm.
Hello. I'm sorry to bother you, but
something rather odd just happened.
It's probably nothing at all,
but you never know.
A young man rang the bell,
asking to use the telephone.
He said there's been
some kind of accident.
The thing that caught my
attention was what he said.
His words sounded like those quoted
in the papers this morning...
...in connection with the writer
and his wife who were assaulted.
COP:
When did this take place, ma'am?
Just a few minutes ago.
I think we'd better send
a patrol car around to see you.
If you think that's necessary.
But I'm quite sure
he's gone away now.
He'll be there in a few minutes.
- All right, fine.
- My pleasure, ma'am.
Thank you very much.
WEATHERS:
Ah!
ALEX:
Hi, hi, hi, there.
At last we meet.
Our brief govorett through the
letter-hole was not satisfactory.
Who are you?
How the hell did you get in here?
What the bloody hell
do you think you're doing?
Naughty, naughty, naughty!
You filthy old soomaka.
Now listen here,
you little bastard!
Just turn round and walk out
of here the same way you came in.
Leave that alone!
Don't touch it!
It's a very important work of art.
What the bloody hell do you want?
To be perfectly honest, madam...
...I'm taking part in an
international students' contest...
...to see who can get the most
points for selling magazines.
Cut the shit, sonny...
...and get out of here before you
get yourself into serious trouble.
I told you to leave that alone!
Now get out of here...
...before I throw you out!
Wretched, slummy bedbug!
I'll teach you to break
into real people's houses.
Fucking...
...little...
...bastard!
WEATHERS:
Ah!
[POLICE SIREN WAILING]
[CATS MEOWING]
ALEX: Let's go. The police are coming!
DIM: One minoota, droogie.
[GUYS CHEERING & LAUGHING]
ALEX:
You bastards!
I'm blind!
I'm blind, you bastards!
I can't see!
[POLICE SIREN WAILING]
It's no good sitting there in hope,
my little brothers.
I won't say a single solitary
slovo unless I have my lawyer here.
I know the law, you bastards.
Righty-right, Tom.
We'll have to show our friend Alex
here that we know the law too.
But that knowing the law
isn't everything.
Nasty cut you've got there,
little Alex.
Shame, isn't it?
Spoils all your beauty.
Who gave you that there?
How'd you do that there?
[BURPS]
ALEX:
Ah! What's that for, you bastard?
That is for your lady victim.
You ghastly...
...wretched scoundrel.
Ah!
Get him off me!
INSPECTOR:
You rotten little bastard!
SERGEANT:
Good evening, Mr. Deltoid.
Good evening, Sergeant.
They're in room B, sir.
Thank you very much.
INSPECTOR:
Sergeant-- Good evening.
Good evening, inspector.
- Would you like your tea now, sir?
- No, thank you, sergeant.
May I have some
paper towels, please?
We're interrogating
the prisoner now.
- Perhaps you'd care to come inside.
- Thank you very much.
Good evening, sergeant.
Good evening, all.
DELTOID: Oh, dear! This boy
does look a mess, doesn't he?
Just look at the state of him.
COP:
Love's young nightmare-like.
INSPECTOR:
Violence makes violence.
He resisted his lawful arrestors.
Well, this is the end of the line for me.
The end of the line, yes.
And what of me, brother sir?
Speak up for me.
I'm not so bad.
I was led on by
the treachery of others.
Sings the roof off lovely,
he does that.
Where are my treacherous droogs?
Get them before they get away!
It was all their idea, brothers.
They forced me to do it.
I'm innocent!
[DELTOID LAUGHING]
You are now a murderer,
little Alex.
A murderer.
Not true, sir.
It was only a slight tolchok.
She were breathing, I swear it.
DELTOID:
I've just come from the hospital.
Your victim has died.
You try to frighten me.
Admit so, sir.
This is some new form of torture.
- Say it, brother sir.
- It'll be your own torture.
I hope to God
it'll torture you to madness.
If you'd care to give him a bash
in the chops, don't mind us.
We'll hold him down.
He must be a great
disappointment to you, sir.
ALEX: This is the real weepy and
tragic part of the story beginning...
...O, my brothers and only friends.
After a trial,
with judges and a jury...
...and hard words spoken against
your friend and humble narrator...
...he was sentenced to 14 years
in Staja Number 84-F...
...among smelly perverts
and hardened prestoopniks.
The shock sending my dada beating
his bruised and krovvy rookers...
...against unfair Bog
in His Heaven.
And my mum boo-hoo-hooing
in her mother's grief...
...at her only child
and son of her bosom...
...like, letting everybody down
real horror show.
GUARD: Morning.
One up from Thames, mister.
One up from Thames, sir.
CHIEF:
Right! Open up the cell!
Yes, sir.
Here are the prisoner's
committal forms.
CHIEF:
Thank you, mister.
CHIEF: Name?
ALEX: Alexander DeLarge.
You are now in
H.M. Prison Parkmoor.
From this moment, you will address
all prison officers as "sir."
- Name?
- Alexander DeLarge, sir.
Sentence?
14 years, sir.
- Crime?
- Murder, sir.
Right.
Take the cuffs off him, mister.
You are now 655321.
It is your duty
to memorize that number.
Thank you, mister. Well done.
- Thank you.
- Let the officer out.
Yes, sir.
All right, empty your pockets.
Are you able to see the white line
painted on the floor...
...directly behind you, 655321 ?
- Yes, sir.
- Then your toes belong...
...on the other side of it!
- Yes, sir.
- Right.
Carry on.
Pick that up
and put it down properly.
One half-bar of chocolate.
One bunch of keys
on white, metal ring.
One packet of cigarettes.
Two plastic ball pens.
One black, one red.
One pocket comb, black plastic.
One...
...address book,
imitation red leather.
One ten-penny piece.
One white, metal wrist let watch.
Timawrist, on a white, metal
expanding bracelet.
Anything else in your pockets?
- No, sir.
- Right.
Sign here for your
valuable property.
The tobacco and chocolate
you brought in...
...you lose that...
...as you are now convicted.
Now over to the table
and get undressed.
Now, then, were you in police custody
this morning?
ALEX: No, sir.
WARDER: One jacket, blue pinstriped.
CHIEF:
Prison custody?
ALEX:
Yes, sir, on remand.
WARDER: One necktie, blue.
CHIEF: Religion?
C of E, sir.
Do you mean the Church of England?
Yes, sir.
The Church of England.
Brown hair, isn't it?
Fair hair, sir.
Blue eyes?
Blue, sir.
- Do you wear eyeglasses or contact lenses?
- No, sir.
One shirt, blue. Collar attached.
Have you been receiving medical
treatment for any serious illness?
- No, sir.
- One pair of boots, black leather.
- Have you had any mental illness?
- No, sir.
- Do you wear false teeth or false limbs?
One pair of trousers,
blue pinstriped.
Have you ever had any attacks
of fainting or dizziness?
- No, sir.
WARDER: One pair of socks, black.
- Are you an epileptic?
- No, sir.
WARDER: One pair of underpants,
white with blue waistband.
Are you now, or have you ever been,
a homosexual?
- No, sir.
- Right.
- The mothballs, mister.
- Mothballs, sir.
Now then, face the wall...
...bend over and touch your toes.
- Any venereal disease?
- No, sir.
- Crabs? Lice?
- Through there for the bath.
WARDER: One for a bath.
What's it going to be, eh?
Is it going to be in and out
of institutions like this...
...though more in than out
for most of you?
Or are you going to attend
to the divine word...
...and realize the punishments
that await unrepentant sinners...
...in the next world
as well as this?
A lot of idiots you are...
...selling your birthright
for a saucer of cold porridge.
The thrill of theft.
Of violence. The urge to live easy.
Well, I ask you what is it worth...
...when we have undeniable proof...
...yes, incontrovertible
evidence...
...that hell exists?
I know!
I know, my friends.
I have been informed...
...in visions...
...that there is a place...
...darker than any prison...
...hotter than any flame
of human fire...
...where souls...
...of unrepentant criminal sinners
like yourselves--
[PRISONER BURPS]
Don't you laugh, damn you!
Don't you laugh.
I say, like yourselves...
...scream...
...in endless and
unendurable agony.
Their skin...
...rotting and peeling.
A fireball...
...spinning in their
screaming guts!
I know. Yes, I know!
[PRISONER FARTS]
[PRISONERS LAUGHING]
[CHIEF SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
Quiet! All right, you lot!
We'll end by singing hymn 258...
...in the prisoner's hymnal.
And let's have a little reverence,
you bastards!
[ALL SINGING "I WAS
A WANDERING SHEEP"]
Come on, sing up, damn you!
Louder!
CHIEF:
ALEX: It had not been edifying.
Indeed not.
Being in this hellhole
and human zoo for two years now.
Being kicked and tolchoked
by brutal warders...
...and meeting leering criminals
and perverts...
...ready to dribble all over...
...a luscious young malchick
like your storyteller.
ALEX:
lt was my rabbit...
...to help the prison charlie
with the Sunday service.
He was a bolshy,
great burly bastard.
But he was very fond of myself,
me being very young...
...and also now very interested
in the Big Book.
MAN:
Move along there!
Move along!
ALEX: I read all about the scourging
and the crowning with thorns.
And I could viddy myself
helping in...
...and even taking charge of
the tolchoking and the nailing in.
Being dressed in the height
of Roman fashion.
I didn't so much like
the latter part of the Book...
...which is more like
all preachy talking...
...than fighting
and the old in-out.
I like the parts where these old
yahoodies tolchok each other...
...and then drink
their Hebrew vino...
...and getting onto the bed
with their wives' handmaidens.
That kept me going.
CHAPLAIN:
"Seek not to be like evil men.
Neither desire to be with them...
...because their minds
studieth robberies...
...and their lips speak deceits."
If thou lose hope, being weary
in the days of distress...
...thy strength
shall be diminished.
Fine, my son. Fine.
Father?
I have tried, have I not?
You have, my son.
- I've done my best, have I not?
- Indeed.
I've never been guilty of any
institutional infraction, have I?
You certainly have not, 655321.
You've been very helpful.
And you've shown
a genuine desire to reform.
Father...
...can I ask you
a question in private?
Certainly, my son. Certainly.
Is there something
troubling you, my son?
Don't be shy to speak up.
Remember...
...I know of the...
...urges that can
trouble young men...
...deprived...
...of the society of women.
Oh, Father.
It's nothing like that, Father.
It's about this new thing
they're all talking about.
About this new treatment.
It gets you out of prison
in no time.
And makes sure you
never get back in again.
Where did you hear about this?
Who's been talking
about these things?
These things get around.
Two warders talk, as it might be.
And somebody can't help
overhearing what they say.
Then somebody picks up a scrap
of newspaper in the workshops...
...and the newspaper
tells all about it.
How about putting me in
for this new treatment?
I take it...
...you are referring...
...to the Ludovico Technique.
I don't know what it's called.
I just know it
gets you out quickly...
...and makes sure you
never get back in again.
That is not proven, 655321.
In fact, it is only in the
experimental stage at this moment.
It is being used, isn't it, Father?
It has not been used
in this prison yet.
The governor has grave
doubts about it.
And I've heard there are
very serious dangers involved.
I don't care about the dangers.
I just want to be good.
I want for the rest
of my life to be...
...one act of goodness.
The question is...
...whether or not this technique...
...really makes a man good.
Goodness comes from within.
Goodness...
...is chosen.
When a man cannot choose...
...he ceases to be a man.
I don't understand...
...about the whys and wherefores.
I only know I want to be good.
Be patient, my son.
Put your trust in the Lord.
Instruct thy son
and he shall refresh thee...
...and shall give delight
to thy soul.
Amen.
CHIEF: Mister!
GUARD: All present and correct, sir!
CHIEF:
Right!
All present and correct!
CHIEF:
Prisoners, halt!
Now pay attention!
I want you in two lines...
...up against that wall,
facing this way.
Go on, move!
Hurry up!
Stop talking!
Prisoners ready
for inspection, sir!
MINISTER:
How many to a cell?
GOVERNOR:
Four in this block, sir.
MINISTER: Cram criminals together
and what do you get?
Concentrated criminality.
Crime in the midst of punishment.
GOVERNOR: I agree, sir. We need
larger prisons, more money.
MINISTER:
Not a chance, my dear fellow.
The government can't be
concerned any longer...
...with outmoded
pen a logical theories.
Soon we may need all prison
space for political offenders.
Common criminals are best dealt
with on a purely curative basis.
Kill the criminal reflex,
that's all.
Full implementation
in a year's time.
Punishment means nothing to them.
They enjoy their
so-called punishment.
You're absolutely right, sir.
Shut your bleeding hole!
MINISTER:
Who said that?
I did, sir.
What crime did you commit?
The accidental killing
of a person, sir.
He brutally murdered a woman
in furtherance of theft.
Fourteen years, sir.
Excellent.
He's enterprising...
...aggressive...
...outgoing...
...young, bold...
...vicious.
He'll do.
Fine.
We could still look at C-block.
No, no. That's enough.
He's perfect.
I want his records sent to me.
This vicious young hoodlum...
...will be transformed
out of all recognition.
Thank you very much
for this chance.
Let's hope you make
the most of it, my boy.
- Shall we go to my office?
- Thank you.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
Come in.
Sir! 655321. Sir!
Very good, chief.
Over to the line.
Toes behind it.
Full name and number
to the governor.
Alexander DeLarge, sir.
655321, sir.
I don't suppose you know who
that was this morning.
That was no less a personage
than the minister of the interior.
The new minister of the interior.
What they call a very new broom.
These new ridiculous ideas
have come at last.
And orders are orders.
Though I may say to you
in confidence, I do not approve.
An eye for an eye, I say.
If someone hits you,
you hit back, do you not?
Why should not the state,
severely hit by you hooligans...
...not hit back also?
The new view is to say "no."
The new view is that
we turn the bad into good.
All of which seems to me
to be grossly unjust.
- Sir, I--
- Shut your filthy hole, you scum!
You are to be reformed.
Tomorrow you will go
to this man, Brodsky.
You will be leaving here.
You will be transferred to
the Ludovico medical facility.
It's believed you'll be able...
...to leave state custody
in a fortnight.
I suppose that prospect
pleases you?
Answer the governor's question!
Yes, sir.
Thank you very much.
I've done my best here,
I really have, sir.
I'm very grateful
to all concerned, sir.
Sign this where it's marked.
Don't read it, sign it!
It says you're willing to have
your sentence commuted...
...to submission to
the Ludovico treatment.
And this.
And another copy.
ALEX:
The next morning I was taken to...
...the Ludovico medical facility...
...outside the town center.
I felt a malenky bit sad...
...having to say goodbye
to the old Staja...
...as you will, when you leave
a place you've gotten used to.
Right, hold the prisoner.
Good morning, sir.
I'm Chief Officer Barnes.
I've got 655321 ...
...on a transfer from Parkmoor
to the Ludovico Centre, sir.
Good morning.
Yes, we've been expecting you.
I'm Dr. Alcot.
Dr. Alcot. Very good, sir.
- Are you prepared for the prisoner?
- Yes, of course.
I wonder if you'd mind signing
these documents, sir.
There, sir.
And there, sir.
And there.
Here you go.
There you are.
Prison escort, move forward!
Halt!
Excuse me, sir.
Is that the officer that is
to take charge of the prisoner?
A word of advice, doc.
You'll have to watch this one.
A right brutal bastard he has been,
and will be again...
...in spite of all his sucking up
and reading the Bible.
We can manage things.
Show the young man to his room.
Right, sir. Come this way, please.
- Morning, Charlie.
- Good morning, doctor.
BRANOM:
Good morning, Alex.
My name is Dr. Branom.
I'm Dr. Brodsky's assistant.
Good morning, missus.
Lovely day.
Indeed, it is.
May I take that?
- How are you feeling?
- Fine, fine.
Good. In a few minutes
you'll meet Dr. Brodsky...
...and begin your treatment.
You're a very lucky boy
to have been chosen.
ALEX: I realize that,
and I'm very grateful to all concerned.
We're going to be friends,
aren't we?
ALEX:
I hope so, missus.
What's the hypo for?
Sending me to sleep?
BRANOM:
Nothing of the sort.
- Vitamins will it be, then?
- Something like that.
You're undernourished.
So after each meal
we'll give you a shot.
Roll over on your right side.
Loosen your pajama pants
and pull them halfway down.
What exactly is the treatment here
going to be, then?
It's quite simple, really.
We're going to show you some films.
You mean like
going to the pictures?
Something like that.
That's good. I like to viddy
the old films now and again.
ALEX:
And viddy films I would.
Where I was taken to, brothers...
...was like no cine
I ever viddied before.
I was bound up
in a straitjacket...
...and my gulliver was strapped
to a headrest...
...with wires running away from it.
Then they clamped, like,
lid-locks on me eyes...
...so that I could not shut them,
no matter how hard I tried.
It seemed a bit crazy to me...
...but I let them get on with
what they wanted to get on with.
If I was to be a free malchick
again in a fortnight...
...I would put up with much
in the meantime, my brothers.
The first film was a very good,
professional piece of cine...
...like it was done in Hollywood.
The sounds were real horror show.
You could slooshy the screams
and moans very realistic.
You could even get
the breathing and panting...
...of the tolchocking malchicks
at the same time.
And then what do you know?
Soon our dear old friend...
...the red, red vino on tap...
...the same in all places...
...like it's put out
by the same firm...
...began to flow.
It was beautiful.
It's funny how the colors
of the real world...
...only seem really real...
...when you viddy them
on a screen.
Now, all the time
I was watching this...
...I was beginning
to get very aware...
...of, like, not feeling
all that well.
And this I put down
to all the rich food and vitamins.
But I tried to forget this,
concentrating on the next film...
...which jumped right away
on a young devotchka...
...who was being given
the old in-out, in-out...
...first by one malchick...
...then another.
Then another.
When it came to
the 6th or 7th malchick...
...leering and smecking
and then going into it...
...I began to feel really sick.
But I could not shut me glazzies.
And even if I tried to move
my glazzballs about...
...I still could not get out of...
...the line of fire
of this picture.
Get me up.
I'm going to be sick.
Get something for me to be sick in!
Very soon now,
the drug will cause the subject...
...to experience
a deathlike paralysis...
...together with deep feelings
of terror and helplessness.
ALEX: I can't stand it anymore.
- One of our early test subjects...
...described it as being like death.
A sense of stifling or drowning.
And it is during this period,
we have found...
...the subject will make
his most rewarding associations...
...between his catastrophic
experience, environment...
...and the violence he sees.
ALEX:
Leave me glazzies!
Dr. Brodsky is pleased with you.
You've made
a very positive response.
Tomorrow there will be two
sessions, morning and afternoon.
You mean I have to viddy
two sessions in one day?
I imagine you'll feel a bit
limp by the end of the day.
But we have to be hard on you.
You have to be cured.
It was horrible.
Of course it was horrible.
Violence is a very horrible thing.
That's what you're learning now.
Your body's learning it.
I just don't understand about
feeling sick the way I did.
I never used to feel sick.
I used to feel the very opposite.
Doing it or watching it,
I used to feel real horror show.
You felt ill this afternoon
because you're getting better.
When we're healthy,
we respond to the hateful...
...with fear and nausea.
You're becoming healthy,
that's all.
By this time tomorrow,
you'll be healthier still.
[BEETHOVEN'S "9TH SYMPHONY"
PLAYING ON FILM]
ALEX:
It was the next day, brothers...
...and I had truly done my best...
...morning and afternoon
to play it their way...
...and sit like a horror show
cooperative malchick...
...in the chair of torture...
...while they flashed nasty bits
of ultra-violence on the screen...
...though not on the soundtrack,
the only sound being music.
Then I noticed,
in all my pain and sickness...
...what music it was
that, like, cracked and boomed.
It was Ludwig van.
Ninth Symphony.
Fourth movement.
ALEX:
Ah!
Ah! Ah!
No! No!
Stop it! Stop it!
Please, I beg you!
It's a sin!
It's a sin! It's a sin! It's a sin!
Sin?
What's all this about sin?
That! Using Ludwig van like that.
He did no harm to anyone.
Beethoven just wrote music.
Are you referring
to the background score?
- Yes!
- You've heard Beethoven before?
Yes!
So you're keen on music?
Can't be helped.
Here's the punishment
element perhaps.
The governor ought to be pleased.
I'm sorry, Alex.
This is for your own good.
You'll have to bear with us
for a while.
But it's not fair. It's not fair
I should feel ill when I hear...
...lovely, lovely Ludwig van.
You must take your chance, boy.
The choice has been all yours.
You needn't take it
any further, sir.
You've proved to me all this
ultra-violence and killing...
...is wrong, wrong
and terribly wrong!
I've learned me lesson, sir.
I see now what I've
never seen before.
I'm cured. Praise God!
You're not cured yet, boy.
But, sirs.
Missus!
I see that it's wrong!
It's wrong because
it's, like, against society.
Because everybody has the
right to live and be happy...
...without being
tolchocked and knifed!
No, no, boy.
You really must leave it to us.
But be cheerful about it.
In less than a fortnight now,
you'll be a free man.
Ladies and gentlemen...
...at this stage, we introduce
the subject himself.
He is, as you will perceive,
fit and well-nourished.
He comes straight from a night's
sleep and a good breakfast...
...undrugged...
...unhypnotized.
Tomorrow we send him out with
confidence into the world again...
...as decent a lad as you
would meet on a May morning.
What a change is here,
ladies and gentlemen.
From the hoodlum
the state committed...
...to unprofitable punishment
some two years ago.
Unchanged after two years.
Unchanged, do I say?
Not quite.
Prison taught him the false smile,
the rubbed hands of hypocrisy.
The fawning, greased,
obsequious leer.
Other vices it taught him...
...as well as confirming him in
those he had long practiced before.
Our party promised
to restore law and order...
...and to make the streets safe for
the ordinary peace-loving citizen.
This pledge is now
about to become a reality.
Ladies and gentlemen,
today is an historic moment.
The problem of criminal violence
is soon to be a thing of the past.
But enough of words.
Actions speak louder than.
Action now.
Observe all.
Our necks are out
a long way on this, minister.
I have complete faith in Brodsky.
If the polls are right,
we have nothing to lose.
Hello, heap of dirt.
[MAN SNIFFING]
Ew. You don't wash much, do you?
Judging by the horrible smell.
ALEX: Why do you say that?
I had a shower this morning.
MAN:
He had a shower this morning.
You trying to call me a liar?
- No, brother.
- You must think I'm awfully stupid.
Why did you do that, brother?
I've never done wrong to you.
You want to know why I did that?
Well, you see...
- ...I do this...
- Ah!
...and that...
...and this because I don't like
your horrible type, do I?
And if you want
to start something...
...you just go ahead. Go on!
Please do!
- I'm going to be sick. I'm going to be sick.
- You're going to be sick, are you?
I'm going to be sick.
Please let me get up.
You want to get up?
Well, now you listen to me.
If you want to get up...
...you've got to
do something for me.
Here.
You see that?
You see that shoe?
I want you to lick it.
Go on!
Lick it.
[ALEX GRUNTING]
ALEX: And, O my brothers,
would you believe...
...your faithful friend
and long-suffering narrator...
...pushed out his red yabzick
a mile and a half...
...to lick the grahzny,
vonny boots.
MAN:
And again!
ALEX: The horrible killing sickness
had whooshed up...
...and turned the joy of battle...
...into a feeling
I was going to snuff it.
MAN:
And again.
Nice and clean.
[ALEX GAGGING]
Thank you very much.
That will do very well.
MAN: Thank you very much,
ladies and gentlemen.
[APPLAUSE]
Thank you very much.
ALEX:
She came towards me...
...with the light, like it was the
light light of heavenly grace.
And the thing that flashed
in me gulliver...
...was that I'd like to have her
there on the floor...
...with the old in-out.
Real savage.
[ALEX GROANING]
But quick as a shot
came the sickness.
Like a detective who'd been
watching around the corner...
...and now followed
to make his arrest.
[GRUNTING & GAGGING]
[ALEX GAGGING]
Enough. Thank you very much.
Thank you, my dear.
[APPLAUSE]
Thank you very much.
Not feeling too bad now, are you?
[ALEX BURPS]
No, sir.
I feel really great, sir.
- Good.
- Was it all right, sir?
- Did I do well?
- Fine, my boy. Absolutely fine.
You see, ladies and gentlemen...
...our subject is impelled
towards the good...
...by paradoxically
being impelled towards evil.
The intention to act violently...
...is accompanied by strong
feelings of physical distress.
To counter these,
the subject has to switch...
...to a diametrically
opposed attitude.
Any questions?
CHAPLAIN:
Choice.
The boy has no real choice, has he?
Self-interest.
The fear of physical pain...
...drove him to that
grotesque act of self-abasement.
Its insincerity
was clearly to be seen.
He ceases to be a wrongdoer.
He ceases also to be
a creature capable of moral choice.
MINISTER:
Padre, these are subtleties.
We're not concerned with motives,
with the higher ethics.
We are concerned only
with cutting down crime.
[APPLAUSE]
MINISTER: And with relieving the
ghastly congestion in our prison.
He will be your true Christian...
...ready to turn the other cheek.
Ready to be crucified,
rather than crucify.
Sick to the very heart at the
thought even of killing a fly.
Reclamation.
Joy before the angels of God.
The point is that it works!
[APPLAUSE]
ALEX: And the very next day,
your friend and humble narrator...
...was a free man.
["I WANT TO MARRY A LIGHTHOUSE
KEEPER" PLAYING ON RADIO]
Son.
- Hi, hi, hi there, my Pee and Em.
- Alex.
Mum.
How are you, love?
Nice to see you.
- Dad.
- Lad. What a surprise.
- Good to see you.
- Keeping fit?
How are you, then?
I'm fine, fine.
Keeping out of trouble, you know.
Well...
I'm back!
Yes. Good to see you.
Why didn't you let us know
what was happening?
Sorry, Em. I wanted it to be, like,
a big surprise for you and Pee.
It's a surprise, all right.
A bit bewildering too.
We've only just read about it
in morning papers.
DAD:
You should have let us know, lad.
Not that we're not very pleased
to see you again, and all...
...cured too, eh?
That's right.
They did a great job on me.
I'm completely reformed.
Well!
Still the same old place, then?
Oh, aye, aye, aye.
Hey, Dad?
There's a strange fellow
sitting on the sofa...
...munchy-wunching
lomticks of toast.
That's Joe.
He lives here now.
The lodger.
That's what he is.
He rents your room.
ALEX:
How do you do, Joe?
Find the room comfortable, do you?
No complaints?
I've heard about you.
I know what you've done.
Breaking the hearts of your
poor, grieving parents.
So you're back, eh?
Back to make life a misery for
your lovely parents once more?
Over my dead corpse, you will.
Because, you see, they've let me
be more like a son to them...
...than like a lodger.
MOTHER: Joe! Joe!
Don't go fighting here, boys.
[GAGGING]
Do put your hand
over your mouth, please.
It's bloody revolting.
[COUGHING]
DAD: Are you all right?
- Shh. It's the treatment.
It's disgusting.
Enough to put you off your food.
Leave him be, Joe.
It's the treatment.
Do you think we ought
to do something?
Would you like me to make you
a nice cup of tea, son?
What have you done
with all me own personal things?
Oh, well...
That was all...
...took away, son.
By the police.
New regulation, see...
...about compensation
for the victims.
What about Basil?
Where's my snake?
Well...
He met with...
...like, an accident.
He passed away.
What's going to happen to me, then?
I mean...
...that's my room he's in.
There's no denying that.
This is my home, also.
What suggestions have you,
my Pee and Em, to make?
All this needs thinking about, son.
We can't very well
just kick Joe out.
Not just like that, can we?
I mean...
...Joe's here doing a job.
A contract it is.
Two years.
We made, like, an arrangement.
Didn't we, Joe?
You see, son...
...Joe's paid next month's
rent already...
...so whatever we may do in
the future, we can't just say...
...to Joe to get out, now can we?
JOE:
No, but it's much more than that.
I mean, I've got you two
to think of...
...who've been like
a father and mother to me.
It wouldn't be right for me
to go off and leave you two...
...to the tender mercies
of this young monster...
...who's been like
no real son at all.
Look, he's weeping now.
But that's all his craft
and artfulness.
Let him go and find
a room somewhere else.
Let him learn the errors
of his way, and that a bad boy...
...doesn't deserve such a good
mum and dad as he's had.
All right.
I know how things are now.
I've suffered and I've suffered...
...and I've suffered.
And everybody wants me
to go on suffering.
[MOTHER CRYING]
You've made others suffer.
It's only right
that you should suffer proper.
I've been told
everything you've done...
...sitting here at night
around the table.
And pretty shocking
it was to listen to.
It made me real sick,
a lot of it did.
[MOTHER CRYING]
Now look what you've gone
and done to your mother.
Come on. It's all right now.
[SNIFFLING]
Right.
I'm leaving now.
You won't ever viddy me no more.
I'll make me own way.
Thank you very much. Let it lie
heavy on your consciences.
DAD:
Now, don't take it like that, son.
[MOTHER CRYING]
All right.
[SEA GULLS SQUAWKING]
Can you spare some cutter,
me brother?
Thanks, brother.
Janie Mack!
May the hokey fly!
Mother of God and all the blessed
saints in heaven preserve us!
I never forget a face, be God!
I never forget any face.
Leave me alone, brother.
I've never seen you before!
This is the poisonous young swine
that near done me in.
Him and his friends.
They beat me and kicked me
and punched me.
Stop him! Stop him!
They laughed at me blood
and me moans, this murderous dog!
ALEX: Then there was like
a sea of dirty, smelly old men...
...trying to get at
your humble narrator...
...with their feeble rookers
and horny old claws.
It was old age
having a go at youth.
And I darenyt do a single
solitary thing, O my brothers.
It being better
to be hit at like that...
...than want to sick
and feel that horrible pain.
OFFICER:
All right, all right! Stop it now.
Come on. Stop breaking the
state's peace, you naughty boys!
Back away! Go away with you!
What's your trouble, sir?
Oh, no.
Well.
Well, well, well.
Well, well, well, well.
If it isn't little Alex.
Long time no viddy, droog.
How goes?
It's impossible.
I don't believe it.
Evidence of the old glazzies.
Nothing up our sleeves.
No magic, little Alex.
A job for two
who are now of job age:
The police.
[DIM & GEORGIE LAUGHING]
DIM:
Come on, Alex.
Come for walking.
[COUGHING]
ALEX: Come, come, come,
my little droogies.
I just don't get this at all.
The old days are dead and gone.
For what I did in the past,
I've been punished.
- I've been cured.
DIM: Cured, yeah. That was read out to us.
The inspector read it
all out to us.
He said it was a very good way.
ALEX:
But what is all this?
It was them
that went for me, brothers.
You're not on their side,
and can't be.
You can't be, Dim.
It was someone we fillied with
back in the old days...
...trying to get his own revenge
after all this time. Remember?
DIM:
A long time is right.
I don't remember them days
too horror show.
And don't call me Dim
no more, either.
"Officer," call me.
GEORGIE: Enough is remembered,
though, little Alex.
DIM: And this is to make sure
you stay cured.
[DIM LAUGHING]
[ALEX GRUNTING]
GEORGIE:
That's enough.
DIM:
A bit more. He's still kicking.
Cured, are you?
Be viddying you some more
sometime, droogie.
[ALEX GRUNTING & PANTING]
[THUNDER CRACKS]
ALEX: Where was I to go,
who had no home and no money?
I cried for meself.
Home, home, home.
It was home I was wanting.
And it was home
I came to, brothers...
...not realizing,
in the state I was in...
...where I was,
and had been before.
[GRUNTING]
[DOORBELL RINGS]
Who on earth could that be?
I'll see who it is.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
Yes, what is it?
[THUNDER CRACKS]
ALEX:
Please...
Frank, I think this young man
needs some help.
FRANK:
My God!
What's happened to you, my boy?
ALEX: And would you believe it,
O my brothers and only friends...
...there was your
faithful narrator...
...being held helpless
like a babe in arms...
...and suddenly realizing
where he was...
...and why "home" on the gate
had looked so familiar.
But I knew I was safe.
I knew he would not remember me.
For in those carefree days...
...I and my so-called droogs...
...wore our maskies, which were
like real horror show disguises.
Police.
Ghastly, horrible police.
They beat me up, sir.
The police beat me up.
I know you!
Isn't it your picture
in the newspapers?
Didn't I see you
on the video this morning?
Are you not the poor victim
of this horrible new technique?
ALEX:
Yes, sir.
That's exactly who I am and
what I am, sir. A victim.
Then, by God, you've been
sent here by providence!
Tortured in prison, then thrown out
to be tortured by the police.
My heart goes out to you poor, poor boy.
You're not the first to come here.
The police like to bring
their victims to this village.
But it's providential that you...
...who are also another kind
of victim, should come here.
But you're cold and shivering.
Julian...
...draw a bath for this young man.
JULIAN:
Certainly, Frank.
ALEX:
Thank you very much.
God bless you.
[THUNDER CRACKS]
[SIGHS]
[HUMMING]
[ALEX SINGING GENE KELLY'S
"SINGIN' IN THE RAIN"]
He can be the most potent
weapon imaginable...
...to ensure the government
is not returned in the election.
The government's big boast, sir...
...is the way they have
dealt with crime:
Recruiting young roughs
into the police...
...proposing will-sapping
techniques of conditioning.
We've seen it before
in other countries.
The thin end of the wedge.
Before we know it, we'll have the
full apparatus of totalitarianism.
This young boy is a living witness
to these diabolical proposals.
The people, the common people,
must know, must see.
There are traditions of liberty to defend.
The tradition of liberty is all.
The common people
will let it go, yes.
They'll sell liberty
for a quieter life.
That is why they must be led.
Driven, pushed.
Fine.
Thank you very much, sir.
He'll be here.
ALEX [SINGING]:
I'm singing in the rain
Just singing in the rain
What a glorious feeling
I'm happy again
I'm laughing at clouds
So dark up above
The sun's in my heart
And I'm ready for love
[BOTH SINGING]
Let the stormy clouds chase
Everyone from the place
Come on with the rain
I've a smile on my face
I'll walk down the lane
To a happy refrain
And I'm singing
In the rain
ALEX:
Good evening, sir.
FRANK:
Good evening.
It was very kind of you
to leave this out for me.
There was no one around,
so I started.
Hope that's all right, sir.
Of course.
Food all right?
Great, sir. Great.
Try the wine.
Thank you, sir.
Cheers.
Happy days.
- Won't you join me?
- No. My health doesn't allow it.
JULIAN:
No, thank you.
"1960, Château.
Saint-Estèphe. Médoc."
Very good brand.
Very good...
...color.
Smells nice too.
Very nice little number.
Well, here's to it.
Very refreshing, sir.
Very refreshing.
I'm pleased you
appreciate good wine.
Have another glass.
Thank you, sir.
FRANK:
My wife...
...used to do everything for me
and leave me to my writing.
Your wife? Is she away?
No. She's dead!
I'm sorry to hear about that.
She was very badly raped, you see.
We were assaulted by
vicious young hoodlums...
...in this very room
you're sitting in now.
I was left a helpless cripple, but
for her the agony was too great.
The doctors said
it was pneumonia...
...because it happened later,
during a flu epidemic.
The doctors told me it was
pneumonia, but I knew what it was.
A victim of the modern age.
Poor, poor girl.
And now, you.
Another victim of the modern age.
But you can be helped.
I phoned some friends while
you were having your bath.
- Some friends, sir?
- Yes. They want to help you.
- Help me?
- Help you.
- Who are they, sir?
- Very, very important people.
And they're interested in you.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
FRANK:
Julian.
This'll be these people now.
I don't want to trouble you
any further. I should be leaving.
No, no, no, my boy. No trouble at all.
Here.
Let me fill your glass.
- Hello, Frank.
FRANK: Good evening sir.
Hello, Frank.
So this is the young man?
- How do you do, sir?
- Hello.
Missus.
I'm very pleased to meet you.
I hope you forgive us for coming
at this hour...
...but we heard you
were in trouble...
...and so we came over to see
if we could help.
Very kind of you, sir.
Thank you very much.
I understand you had a rather...
...unfortunate...
...encounter...
...with the police tonight.
Yes, I suppose
you could call it that.
DOLIN:
How are you feeling now?
Much better, thank you.
DOLIN: Feel like talking,
answering a few questions?
Fine, sir. Fine.
As I said, we've heard about you.
We are interested in your case.
- We want to help you.
- Thank you very much.
Shall we get down to it?
ALEX:
Fine. Fine, sir.
The newspapers mentioned...
...that in addition to your being
conditioned against...
...acts of sex and violence...
...you've inadvertently been
conditioned against music.
I think that was something
that they didn't plan for.
You see, missus...
...I'm very fond of music.
Especially Beethoven.
Ludwig van Beethoven.
- B-E--
- It's all right. Thank you.
And it just so happened that
while they were showing me...
...a particularly bad film
of, like, a concentration camp...
...the background music
was playing Beethoven.
So now you have
the same reaction to music...
...as you do to sex and violence?
No, missus. You see, it's not
all music. It's just the "9th."
You mean Beethoven's "9th Symphony"?
That's right. I can't listen
to the "9th" anymore at all.
When I hear the "9th," I get, like...
...this funny feeling.
And then all I can think about
is, like, trying to snuff it.
- I beg your pardon?
- Snuff it. Death, I mean.
I just want to die peacefully...
...like, with no pain.
DOLIN:
Do you feel that way now?
No, sir, not exactly.
I still feel...
...very miserable.
Very much down in spirits.
Do you still feel...
...suicidal?
Put it this way:
I feel very low in meself.
I can't see much in the future.
I feel that any second, something
terrible is going to happen to me.
DOLIN:
Well done, Frank.
Julian. Get the car, would you, please?
[BEETHOVEN'S "9TH SYMPHONY"
PLAYING ON STEREO]
ALEX:
I woke up.
[BURPS]
The pain and sickness
all over me like an animal.
[GRUNTING]
Then I realized what it was.
The music coming up
from the floor...
...was our old friend,
Ludwig van...
...and the dreaded "9th Symphony."
Let me out!
Open the door!
Come on, open the door!
Ah! Turn it off!
Turn it off!
Stop it!
[BEETHOVEN'S "9TH SYMPHONY"
PLAYING ON STEREO]
Turn it off!
[THUMPING & POUNDING ON CEILING]
Please! Turn it off!
[GAGGING]
ALEX: Suddenly, I viddied
what I had to do...
...and what I had wanted to do.
And that was to do myself in.
To snuff it.
To blast off forever,
out of this wicked, cruel world.
One moment of pain, perhaps...
...and then sleep.
Forever and ever...
...and ever.
Ah!
ALEX:
I jumped, O my brothers...
...and I fell hard.
But I did not snuff it.
If I had snuffed it...
...I would not be here
to tell what I told have.
I came back to life
after a long, black, black gap...
...of what might have been
a million years.
[ALEX MOANS]
[WOMAN MOANS]
NURSE:
Oh.
He's recovered
consciousness, doctor.
Hello, lad.
Hello, son.
How are you?
You feeling better?
What...
...gives...
...O my Pee and Em?
What makes...
...you think you are welcome?
[SNIFFLING]
There, there, Mother.
It's all right.
He doesn't mean it.
You were in the papers again, son.
It said...
...they had done
great wrong to you.
It said...
...how the government...
...drove you to try...
...and do yourself in.
And when you think about it, son...
...maybe it was our fault too...
...in a way.
Your home's your home...
...when all's said and done, son.
- Good morning.
- Good morning, doctor.
- Good morning, missis.
- How are you feeling today?
- Fine.
Good. May I?
- I'm Dr. Taylor.
- Haven't seen you before.
I'm your psychiatrist.
Psychiatrist!
Do I need one?
Just part of hospital routine.
Are we going to
talk about me sex life?
Oh, no.
I'm going to show you
some slides...
...and you're going to tell me
what you think about them.
Jolly good.
You know anything about dreams?
Something, yes.
- You know what they mean?
- Perhaps.
You concerned about something?
No, not concerned, really...
...but I've been having
this nasty dream.
Very nasty.
It's like...
Well, when I was all smashed up,
you know...
...and half-awake
and unconscious-like...
...I kept having this dream.
All these doctors were
playing around with me gulliver.
You know, like the inside
of me brain.
I seem to have this dream
over and over again.
Do you think it means anything?
Patients with injuries like yours
often have dreams of this sort.
- It's all part of the recovery process.
- Oh.
Now then, each of these slides
needs a reply...
...from one of the people
in the picture.
You tell me what you think
the person would say. All right?
Righty-right.
TAYLOR:
"isn't the plumage beautiful?"
- I just say what the other person would say?
- Yes.
"Isn't the plumage beautiful?"
Don't think about it too long.
Say the first thing
that pops into your mind.
Cabbages. Knickers.
It's not got a beak.
TAYLOR:
Good.
[LAUGHS]
TAYLOR: "The boy you always
quarreled with is seriously ill."
My mind is a blank...
...and I'll smash your face
for you, yarblockos.
TAYLOR:
Good.
"What do you want?"
No time for the old in-out, love.
I've just come to read the meter.
Good.
TAYLOR: "You sold me a crummy
watch. I want my money back.
You know what you can do with
that watch? Stick it up your ass!
TAYLOR:
Good.
TAYLOR: "You can do
whatever you like with these."
Eggiwegs.
I would like...
...to smash them.
And pick them all up...
...and throw-- Ow!
Fucking hell!
There. That's all there is to it.
Are you all right?
Hope so.
Is that the end, then?
I was quite enjoying that.
Good. I'm glad.
- How many did I get right?
- It's not that kind of a test.
But you seem well on the way
to making a complete recovery.
When do I get out, then?
TAYLOR:
I'm sure it won't be long now.
ALEX:
So I waited.
And, O my brothers...
...I got a lot better...
...munching away at eggiwegs
and lomticks of toast...
...and lovely steakie-wakes.
And then one day...
...they said I was going to have
a very special visitor.
DOCTOR: Just wait outside for
a moment, would you, officer.
MINISTER: I'm afraid my change
of schedule has thrown you.
The patient's in the middle
of supper.
DOCTOR: That's quite all right,
minister. No trouble at all.
- Good evening, my boy.
ALEX: Hi there, my little droogies.
How're you getting on, young man?
Great, sir. Just great.
Can I do anything more for you?
I don't think so, Sir Leslie.
Then I leave you to it. Nurse.
You seem to have a whole ward
to yourself, my boy.
Yes, sir.
And a very lonely place
it is too...
...when I wake up in the night
with me pain.
Yes. Anyway, good to see you
on the mend.
I kept in touch
with the hospital, of course.
And now I've come down
personally...
...to see how you're getting along.
I've suffered the tortures
of the damned.
Tortures of the damned.
Yes, I can appreciate that
you've had an extremely--
Oh, look. Let me help you
with that, shall I?
Thank you, sir. Thank you.
I can tell you that I, and the
government of which I'm a member...
...are deeply sorry about this,
my boy. Deeply sorry.
We tried to help you.
We followed recommendations
that turned out to be wrong.
An inquiry will place the
responsibility where it belongs.
We want you to regard us
as friends.
We put you right.
You're getting
the best of treatment.
We never wished you harm.
But there are some who did, and do.
And I think you know who those are.
There are certain people who wanted
to use you for political ends.
They would have been
glad to have you dead...
...for they thought they could then
blame it on the government.
There is also a certain man...
...a writer of subversive
literature...
...who has been howling
for your blood.
He's been mad with desire
to stick a knife into you.
But you're safe from him now.
We put him away.
He found out that you
had done wrong to him.
At least he believed
you had done wrong.
He formed this idea in his head
that you had been responsible...
...for the death of someone
near and dear to him.
He was a menace.
We put him away
for his own protection.
And also for yours.
Where is he now?
We put him away
where he can do you no harm.
You see, we are looking
after your interests.
We are interested in you.
When you leave, you'll have no
worries. We'll see to everything.
A good job on a good salary.
What job and how much?
You'll have an interesting job at
a salary you regard as adequate.
Not only for the job
you're going to do...
...and in compensation for what
you believe you have suffered...
...but also because
you are helping us.
Helping you?
We always help our friends,
don't we?
It is no secret
that this government...
...has lost a lot of popularity
because of you, my boy.
There are some who think that at
the next election we shall be out.
The press has chosen to take
a very unfavorable view...
...of what we tried to do.
But public opinion
has a way of changing.
And you, Alex--
If I may call you Alex...
Certainly, sir.
What do they call you at home?
[MINISTER CLEARS THROAT]
My name is Frederick.
As I was saying, Alex...
...you can be instrumental
in changing the public's verdict.
Do you understand, Alex?
Do I make myself clear?
As an unmuddied lake, Fred.
As clear as an azure sky
of deepest summer.
- You can rely on me, Fred.
- Good.
Good boy.
Oh, yes. I understand you're fond of music.
I have arranged a little
surprise for you.
Surprise?
One that I hope
that you will like...
...as a...
How shall we put it?
As a symbol of
our new understanding.
An understanding
between two friends.
[BEETHOVEN'S "9TH SYMPHONY"
PLAYING ON SPEAKERS]
ALEX:
I was cured, all right.